Work hard. Fail hard.
BlackBerry is a comedy, drama, history film directed by Matt Johnson.
Two mismatched entrepreneurs – egghead innovator Mike Lazaridis and cut-throat businessman Jim Balsillie –
joined forces in an endeavour that was to become a worldwide hit in little more than a decade.
The story of the meteoric rise and catastrophic
demise of the world's first smartphone.
Mike Lazaridis, played by Jay Baruchel.
Jim Balsillie, played by Glenn Howerton.
Doug Fregin, played by Matt Johnson.
Charles Purdy, played by Michael Ironside.
Carl Yankowski, played by Cary Elwes.
John Woodman, played by Saul Rubinek.
BlackBerry is a 2023 Canadian biographical comedy-drama film directed by Matt
Johnson from a screenplay by Johnson and producer Matthew Miller.
It was loosely adapted from Jacquie McNish and Sean Silcoff's book Losing the Signal: The
Untold Story Behind the Extraordinary Rise and Spectacular Fall of BlackBerry.
The film is a dramatized account of the history of the BlackBerry line of mobile phones created
by co-founders Douglas Fregin and Mike Lazaridis, and investor Jim Balsillie.
Lazaridis is portrayed by Jay Baruchel, Balsillie is portrayed by
Glenn Howerton, and Fregin is portrayed by Johnson.
The film also stars Rich Sommer, Michael Ironside, Martin Donovan, Michelle Giroux,
SungWon Cho, Mark Critch, Saul Rubinek, and Cary Elwes in supporting roles.
BlackBerry premiered in competition at the 73rd Berlin
International Film Festival on February 17, 2023.
The film was released in Canada on May 12, 2023, to positive reviews.
In late 2023, Blackberry was re-released as a
three-part miniseries with additional footage.
The film is the most nominated film in the history of the
Canadian Screen Awards, with 17 nominations.
It won 14 awards, including Best Motion Picture.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
technology, it-expert, silicon valley, satire.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.